

Phone (+34) 659 296 478

Email saez240@gmail.com

Twitter & Figma ID

@esaez

Website & Portfolio about.me/enriquesm

Languages

Spanish, mother tongue English, B1-B2 Portuguese, C1

Soft Skills

Work with minimal supervision
Interesting in updating knowledge
Accustomed to teamwork
Good communicator

Enrique Sáez Mata

Product UX Designer

Senior Product Designer and UI developer, +10 years working at the IT sector, I have worked for several companies and clients, usually in Digital Transformation projects and fintech projects, among others.

Experience

Apr 2015 — Present Madrid and London	0	Senior UI Designer - UI Developer GFT Technologies
Jan 2015 — Apr 2015 Madrid, Spain	0	Senior UI Designer - UI Developer Alten Spain
Oct 2013 — Dec 2014 São Paulo, Brazil		Senior UI - UX Designer Captalis SL - MoneyGuru
Jan 2011 — Oct 2013 Córdoba		Senior UI Developer - UI Developer Freelance
Jan 2003 — Dec 2010 Madrid, Spain	0	Visual Designer - UI Developer TasGroup SL

Skills - Technology Stack

0	Web Prototype
0	Visual communication
0	User empathy
UX Design	Invision, Zeplin
0	Adobe CC
0	Figma
0	Sketch
0	Semantic HTML5
0	CSS3 > Flexbox, Grid system, Responsive.
0	BEM, OOCSS, BEMIT, SMACSS
UI Develop O	Javascript, Reactjs, Angularjs prototyping.
0	SASS, LESS precompilers
0	GIT, GitHub, SVN
	Agile, Scrum, Kanban methodologies

Education

1997 • University of Córdoba - UCO
Production of Web and Multimedia content.

1990-1994 • Escuela de Arte Mateo Inurria
Graduated in Arts. Advertising Specialty.

Career Highlights

O As a member of BBVA Design Spain

Founder of the "Layout Team" of UI development and later in charge of UI development in the Enterprise Global Solutions group.

Team member in other fintech projects within multidisciplinary frontend teams, as UI developer or UX designer, depending on the needs. Also in other fintech projects, with clients such as Banc Sabadell, Deustche Bank or Repsol.

• As a Senior UI Developer in MoneyGuru (Brazil)

Head of the department of web design, interaction and user experience of the corporate websites of its clients.

In charge of the design department, web prototyping tasks, interaction, user experience on the website, managing to exponentially increase visits and Leds generation, to later be responsible for web migration and restyling of the brand at the headquarters in São Paulo, Brazil.